What are AI agents?
What are the best use cases for them?
And what do we need to start building them?
We're going to answer these questions
in this first lesson of the AI agents for beginners course.
In this course, we're going to take you from concept to code
covering the fundamentals of building AI agents.
And in this short video, it follows along
with the written lesson, including translations
and a code sample that you can find the link to
above and below this video.
Well, let's get started looking at the parts of an AI agent.
And the first part is a large language model,
which powers the reasoning behind our AI agents.
And what we mean by reasoning is being able to identify
a task requested by users, create a plan to complete
that task and perform the actions of that plan.